Kyler Bomhof

Software Developer

616.405.0409 kdbomhof@gmail.com github.com/senyc Grand Rapids, MI

EXPERIENCE

kylerbomhof.com

07/2023 - Present

A mobile-centric website that highlights my skills, experience, and projects. Developed using Next.js, styled with Tailwind CSS and Material UI, and hosted on Vercel.

typetest-cli

06/2023 - Present

A lightweight type speed tester for the terminal written in Python. Published to PyPI, and easily installable with pip on any machine that can run Python.

Software Developer Intern

Auto-Owners Insurance

05/2023 - Present

As a software developer I primarily built full stack applications to reduce labor-intensive maintenance task by agents.

I followed the Scrum framework while collaborating with a team of business analysts, quality assurance engineers, and other software developers.

I was personally responsible for front and back-end architectural decisions as well as their implementation. I largely used React.js, Typescript, Node, and SQL server.

Information Technology Intern

Haworth

05/2022 - 05/2023

I worked with members of the Information Security team to roll out new security software to over 7,000 devices.

I Wrote and deployed scripts using Microsoft Endpoint, Azure AD, and Configuration Manager.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Michigan Technological University Bachelor of Science - B.Sc

Dec. 2023

- GPA of 3.62
- Member of University Innovation Fellows
- IT Oxygen team lead working with machine learning

SUMMARY

Software developer passionate about the systems he writes, and software he architects. Personal advocate for keeping code testable, and actually tested.

Kyler has Professional experience with full-stack development, working with teams, and utilizing the scrum framework.

SKILLS

Typescript/JS Advanced

Python Expert

Go Intermediate

React.js Advanced
Node.js Advanced
Linux Advanced

tailwindcss Intermediate

Bash Advanced

Git Expert

SQL Intermediate CSS/SCSS Intermediate

Lua Intermediate
C Advanced

C++ Intermediate

Vim Expert

Ruby Intermediate

Intermediate

Object Oriented Programming

Time Management

Agile Methodologies

Team Management

Testing